

April Baker

2 teach is2 touch lives4 ever

tbaker152@msn.com

1144 Morgan Hill Drive Pennsburg, PA 18073 **267-343-2501**

Summary

Enthusiastic Level 2- Dual Certified Elementary and Special Education Teacher with 8 years of experience and a MA in Teaching and Learning with Technology, easily cultivates a trusting and productive relationship with students, parents, teachers and administration.

Experience

Special Education Coordinator at Education Plus Academy Cyber School

09/2012 - 03/2014

- Initiated and managed a synchronous Virtual Learning Program incorporating innovative technology with state of the art curriculum for greater learning opportunities
- Trained Teachers on Special Education documentation and procedures
- Trained and mentored K-8 Teachers on Virtual Teaching Platforms and Blackboard Collaborate
- Taught students in grades K-8 using an Online Collaborative classroom
- Wrote IEPs, and RR's and conducted IEP meetings
- Individualized and employed special educational strategies and techniques during instruction to improve the development of sensory/perceptual-motor skills, language, cognition and memory
- Worked collaboratively with my student's parents and guardians to encourage student engagement

Job Coach at Teamwork Wins

09/2011 - 06/2012

- Accompanied and Coached High School Students at their work experience
- Completed daily and quarterly IEP evaluations

Special Education Teacher at Agora Cyber Charter School

09/2009 - 06/2011

- Virtual Middle School Special Education Teacher
- Wrote IEPs, and RR's and conducted IEP meetings

- Taught synchronously over Blackboard Collaborate, incorporating innovative K-12 Curriculum and technology for greater learning opportunities
- Worked collaboratively with my student's parents and guardians to encourage student engagement

Licensed Kindermusik Instructor at Milford Music Studio and Lifespan

09/2001 - 09/2009

- Taught music to children ranging from ages 0-6 years-old

Special Education Teacher at Children's Developmental Program

07/2000 - 08/2001

- Taught children with special needs ages 2-5 years-old
- Wrote IEP's, CER's and conducted regular meetings with parents, therapists and social workers

Learning Support Teacher at Neidig Elementary School

03/2000 - 06/2000

- Long Term Substitute- Taught Reading and Math to students who needed extra support
- Wrote IEP's and Conducted IEP meetings

Special Education Teacher at Carson Valley School

09/1999 - 06/2000

- Taught Reading and Language Arts to behaviorally and psychologically challenged students ages 11-16
- Wrote IEP's and Conducted IEP meetings

Special Education Teacher at Wood School

09/1998 - 06/1999

- Taught Life Skills to behaviorally and psychologically challenged students ages 13-21
- Wrote IEP's and Conducted IEP meetings

Education



Master of Arts (M.A.), Teaching and Learning with Technology, Grade: 4.0/4.0



Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Elementary and Special Education



Associate of Arts (A.A.), Visual and Performing Arts

Certification



Interest and Talent

